# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello everyone, I'm Wang Gang
# 最近收到后台一些私信
Recently I received some private messages
# 就是其他作者问我们整个工作室到拍摄要花多少钱
Other authors asked us how much would it cost to set up the entire studio to shoot videos
# 然后我就算了一笔账
Then, I made a calculation
# 从我们回来的时候
Since we got back
# 从2017年到现在我们这个房租押金是5千然后房租是1万5一年
from 2017 to now, our rent deposit is 5,000 yuan, and the rent is 15,000 yuan per year
# 交了4万5千块钱的房租加押金
We paid 45,000 yuan in rent and deposit
# 反正这一块就5万块钱
Anyway, all these together cost about 50,000 yuan
# 然后就是我回来的时候这个门面它是一个比较长的一个门面
When we came back, it was a long shopfront
# 宽的话是3米5 长的话大概是10米多一点
It was 3.5m wide, and about 10m long
# 总共是40多个平方
More than 40 square meters in total
# 刚开始我们接手的时候这个门面是毛坯（房） 什么都没有
When we took over the shopfront, it was a vanilla box with nothing in it
# 然后我们回来搞了一下装修
Then we came back and did some decoration
# 就吊了顶 做了墙面 然后还有这个地板
we installed suspended ceiling, decorated walls and laid floor
# 这一块装修大概总共花了2万块钱左右
The whole decoration cost was about 20,000 yuan in total
# 大部分的装修做完了之后呢
After most of the decorating was done
# 就要做排水 排烟道 水电气 这一块也比较贵
the following was to do the drainage, exhaust duct, as well as water, electricity and gas supply. They were also expensive
# 因为我们这个门面它以前是做的库房 没有排水
Cuz our shopfront used to be a warehouse, there was no drainage in it
# 我们挖这个排水管从这边一直挖到街上去
Our drainpipe was dug from here to the street
# 挖得距离有点远 所以有点贵
A little far, so it was a bit expensive
# 总共大概2万块钱左右
In all, we spent about 20,000 yuan
# 我们这块水电气装修吊顶地板做完了之后开始买设备
After finishing all those mentioned above, we needed to buy equipments
# 设备的话就包括我后面上面这个烟罩 这个炉具
Including the range hood above, the ranges
# 还有一些打荷台之类的东西 还有冰箱
and some other things like "Da He Tai" (Spreader table), and refrigerator
# 还有不锈钢的比如说这种盆盆罐罐的这些东西
Also something stainless steel, like these pots and pans
# 总共花了1万5左右
All these stuff cost me about 15,000 yuan
# 其实这一块因为这一块我是专业的嘛
In fact, I'm a professional in this area
# 就是没有买贵 也没有被人家坑
So I neither spent too much money nor got scammed
# 有的东西我买的是二手的 所以就便宜很多
Some stuff I bought was secondhand, so it was much cheaper
# 然后剩下的就是一些厨房的工具
Then, everything else was kitchen tools
# 刀具啊 砧板啊 还有一些餐具之类的
Like knives, cutting boards and utensils
# 这一块大概花了3、4千
These cost about 3,000 to 4,000 yuan
# 总的算下来的话 我们不包括拍摄的设备
All together, excluding the video equipment
# 到目前为止总共投资了大概10万块钱
We've invested about 100,000 yuan so far
# 我17年回来的时候就是自己做厨师长攒了一点钱
When I came back in 2017, I had saved some money as being a chef
# 然后用我老婆的信用卡刷了几万块钱
Then I spent ten thousands of yuan with my wife's credit card
# 然后借了我亲戚一些钱来做这个工作室
Also borrowed some money from my relatives to make this studio
# 刚开始的时候别人说我们比较傻
At first people said we were stupid
# 这个位置又偏 门面的话又不当道
The location was out of the street
# 然后租金也不便宜 1千多块钱一个月
and the rent was not cheap either, more than 1,000 yuan a month
# 问我做这个东西来干什么
They asked me what I was doing with it
# 开馆子的话位置又差
If I opened a restaurant, it would be in a bad location
# 投资了这么多钱进去说我比较傻
They said I was silly to invest so much money in it
# 然后这几年一步一步走过来
But I moved on step by step over the years
# 我在这个地方拍了几百个视频
I made hundreds of videos in this place
# 如果你们除了对这个（工作室）感兴趣之外
If you're interested in anything besides this (studio)
# 你们想看一下我拍摄的设备的话
say you wanna take a look at my video equipment
# 下一期我可以给你们做一期视频
I can make it in my next video
# 好了 今天的视频就到这里
OK, that's all for today's vedio
# 总结一下这一块做了几年
Let's have a summary. I've been engaged in this area for a few years
# 花了十多万 比较值
and have spent over 100,000 yuan, but it's worth it
# 就不说其他的 就拍了这么多视频
Apart from other things, I've made so many videos
# 跟大家分享了这么多教学做菜
And shared so many cooking videos
# 我觉得值了 这钱花的从心底里面来说很值
I think it's worth it. From the bottom of my heart, that's worth the money
# 好了本期视频就到这里 拜拜
All right, that's all for this video. Bye bye